<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>dns on King&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.kingtam.tk/tags/dns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dns on King&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 16:34:07 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kingtam.tk/tags/dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Renew DNS Servers in VMWare ESXi via ESXCLI Commands</title>
      <link>https://www.kingtam.tk/posts/esxi-dns-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 16:34:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kingtam.tk/posts/esxi-dns-update/</guid>
      <description>Renew DNS Servers in VMWare ESXi via ESXCLI Commands About Issue If you need to renew DNS servers on an ESXi host and are having trouble finding the DNS field in the ESXi portal, you can use ESXCLI commands to update the DNS servers.
Procedure Enable SSH Service first on ESXi Open a console or SSH session to the ESXi host. 1 ssh root@esxi_ip_address List Current DNS server IP Address Run the command 1 esxcli network ip dns server list DNSServers: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up SmartDNS in Alpine Linux (LXC)</title>
      <link>https://www.kingtam.tk/posts/alpine-smartdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 12:08:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kingtam.tk/posts/alpine-smartdns/</guid>
      <description>Set up SmartDNS in Alpine Linux (LXC) SmartDNS is a local DNS server that retrieves DNS query results from multiple upstream DNS servers and delivers the fastest results to clients. It supports secure DNS protocols such as DoT (DNS over TLS) and DoH (DNS over HTTPS), providing enhanced privacy protection, avoiding DNS pollution, and improving network access speed. Additionally, SmartDNS supports high-performance ad filtering for an overall better browsing experience</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpine Linux as a DHCP and DNS Server</title>
      <link>https://www.kingtam.tk/posts/alpine-dhcp-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 11:14:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kingtam.tk/posts/alpine-dhcp-dns/</guid>
      <description>dnsmasq is a lightweight, easy-to-configure DHCP and DNS server. I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to set up dnsmasq as both a DHCP and DNS server on a Linux system.
Procedure Procedure Network Card Configuration : Network Card Configuration 1 ip address The physical interface eth1 is used to set up DHCP and DNS services.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 cat &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/network/interfaces &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF auto eth1 iface eth1 inet static address 192.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
