<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on King&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on King&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 13:39:16 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuring VLANs on a Host for PVE (Proxmox VE)</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/pve-host-vlan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 13:39:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/pve-host-vlan/</guid>
      <description>Configuring VLANs on a Host for Proxmox VE In today&amp;rsquo;s increasingly complex networking environments, Virtual Local Area Networks (VLANs) have become a crucial tool for managing network traffic and ensuring optimal performance.
This blog post provides a step-by-step guide on configuring VLANs on a host for Proxmox Virtual Environment (VE), a popular open-source virtualization platform.
Why use VLANs with Proxmox VE? VLANs allow you to segregate network traffic into isolated broadcast domains, improving security and reducing network congestion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PVE (Proxmox VE) Multi-port Identification</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/pve-network-port/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 13:04:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/pve-network-port/</guid>
      <description>PVE (Proxmox VE) Multi-port Identification About: This is a post about network card (multiple ports) identification in the PVE system. Through the ethtool command, you can easily find the corresponding location of each network port.
Operation Steps: Take Intel EXPI9402PTBLK 82571GB Network Adapter as an example
Install the ethtool command
1 apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt install ethtool -y ethtool can be used to view network device driver parameters and hardware configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use WINSW To Setup FRP As Windows Service</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/winsw-frpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 10:06:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/winsw-frpc/</guid>
      <description>About: WinSW is a utility that allows you to wrap and manage a Windows service for any executable.
frpc is a client for the frp (Fast Reverse Proxy) tool, which enables you to expose local servers to the internet.
Procedure: To set up frpc as a Windows service using WinSW, follow these steps:
Download WinSW Download the latest release of WinSW from the releases page. Choose the appropriate executable for your system, either WinSW-x64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing CUPS on PVE&#39;s LXC Container System</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/pve-lxc-cups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 14:55:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/pve-lxc-cups/</guid>
      <description>Installing CUPS on PVE&amp;rsquo;s LXC Container System Introduction: At home, I use a Canon LBP6030 USB printer connected to a Padavan system on a router (Youku1) to enable wireless printing. However, wireless printing can only be achieved on the Windows platform, and on systems such as macOS and IOS from Apple, it cannot be achieved, causing some inconvenience.
I came across this post on SMZDM N1刷armbian變身打印服務器, which can install CUPS software as a printer server system, and thus the following content was recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing LXC in Proxmox Virtual Environment (PVE)</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/pve-lxc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 13:08:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/pve-lxc/</guid>
      <description>We will explore the syntax of managing LXC using PVE. Use commands that are commonly used by system administrators and cover the basics of creating, removing, and managing LXC in PVE.
What&amp;rsquo;s LXC? LXC is a user space interface for the Linux kernel containment features. Through a powerful API and simple tools, it lets Linux users easily create and manage system or application containers.
Template Image Creating an LXC in PVE is to download a template image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up SmartDNS in Alpine Linux (LXC)</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-smartdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 12:08:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-smartdns/</guid>
      <description>Set up SmartDNS in Alpine Linux (LXC) SmartDNS is a local DNS server that retrieves DNS query results from multiple upstream DNS servers and delivers the fastest results to clients. It supports secure DNS protocols such as DoT (DNS over TLS) and DoH (DNS over HTTPS), providing enhanced privacy protection, avoiding DNS pollution, and improving network access speed. Additionally, SmartDNS supports high-performance ad filtering for an overall better browsing experience</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpine Linux share the terminal over the web (ttyd)</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-ttyd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 12:03:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-ttyd/</guid>
      <description>What is ttyd? What is ttyd? ttyd is a simple command-line program that allows you to share a terminal session over the web. It provides a web-based terminal interface for interacting with a Linux system, making it possible to access the system remotely from a web browser.
Install ttyd in Alpine Linux Install ttyd in Alpine Linux Open the terminal and type the following command to update the packages list:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpine Linux as a DHCP and DNS Server</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-dhcp-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 11:14:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-dhcp-dns/</guid>
      <description>dnsmasq is a lightweight, easy-to-configure DHCP and DNS server. I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to set up dnsmasq as both a DHCP and DNS server on a Linux system.
Procedure Procedure Network Card Configuration : Network Card Configuration 1 ip address The physical interface eth1 is used to set up DHCP and DNS services.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 cat &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/network/interfaces &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF auto eth1 iface eth1 inet static address 192.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpine Linux-based LXC with Docker support on a PVE host</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-lxc-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 11:14:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-lxc-docker/</guid>
      <description>Setting up an Alpine Linux-based Container (LXC) with Docker support on a Proxmox Virtual Environment (PVE) host.
Lightweight and secure: Alpine Linux is a lightweight and secure distribution of Linux that is ideal for use in containers. It has a small footprint and is designed to minimize attack surface, making it a good choice for running Docker containers. Flexibility: Using an LXC container allows you to run multiple instances of Docker on a single host, each with its own isolated environment and resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpine Linux Customizations</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-customization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 11:03:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-customization/</guid>
      <description>One of the benefits of using Alpine Linux is its flexibility and customizability, which allows users to tailor the system to their specific needs.
Setting the timezone Check the current timezone
1 date Timezone setting
1 setup-timezone Which timezone are you in? (&amp;rsquo;?&amp;rsquo; for list) [UTC] Asia/Hong_Kong
Suppose you want to use the Asia/ timezone and Hong_Kong as the sub-timezone of &amp;lsquo;Asia/&amp;rsquo;. You can input &amp;lsquo;?&amp;rsquo; to list the timezones to choose from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpine Linux Package Management Tool</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-apk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 09:12:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-apk/</guid>
      <description>About The package management tool used in Alpine Linux is apk. apk is a fast, lightweight, and efficient package management tool that has the following features:
Native support for cross-compilation and cross-platform installation. Automatic handling of dependencies when installing and uninstalling packages. Support for multiple repositories, including official repositories, community repositories, and personal repositories. Simple command-line interface that allows users to perform various operations such as search, install, upgrade, and uninstall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpine Installation</title>
      <link>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 09:03:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.kingtam.cf/posts/alpine-installation/</guid>
      <description>Why Alpine Linux Alpine Linux is a lightweight, security-focused, rolling release distribution with a fast and efficient package manager. It is highly customizable and compatible with a wide range of hardware architectures, making it suitable for use in a variety of environments.
Preparation Download the Alpine Linux ISO image file from the official website: https://alpinelinux.org/downloads/ Write the ISO image file to a USB drive using a tool such as Rufus or Etcher.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
